ikeafans.com 2012-12-30

# Privacy Policy

IKEA® is a trademark of Inter IKEA Systems B.V. which does not sponsor, authorize or endorse this site.

_Updated April 11, 2011_

### THE ESSENCE

We want you to be comfortable in the knowledge that your personal information is held in the strictest confidence -- IKEAFANS is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only for the express purpose for which you are providing it and will always be used in accordance with this privacy statement. Personal information will never be sold, traded, shared, distributed, leased or given to third parties. 

This Privacy Policy is effective immediately, and may be updated at any time. If there are changes to this policy we will do our level best to inform all members of the change and provide a link to this page. Continued use of the site constitutes your acceptance of the revised policy. 

### WHAT WE COLLECT

No personally identifiable information is collected, with the exception of information entered explicitly by the user in the course of establishing a membership. 

In addition, we may collect the following statistical (NOT personally identifiable) information, including but not limited to: 

  * User geographical location and/or distance to IKEA
  * Local IKEA location
  * Referral sources,
  * Household makeup and income level,
  * Gender
  * Birthdate
  * User browser/platform versions,
  * And website page traffic statistics, including flow patterns and entrance/exit points.

Also, within the forum software, IP addresses are tracked and are stored in the forums database. The sole reason that IP's are collected is for self-protection; if we are hacked, spammed or otherwise attacked, we would be able to resolve the issue to a specific IP address. IP addresses are not used in any other fashion. If you are not comfortable with this limited usage, you must realize that your only recourse is to not use the website. 

### WHAT WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER

We gather this information in order to better understand the needs of our visitors and members, to provide you with better service, and for the following reasons: 

  * Internal record keeping and statistical analysis.
  * To improve our products and services and bring better IKEA information to you.
  * To optimize the website according to visitor and member needs.

### SECURITY

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### HOW WE USE COOKIES and WEB BEACONS

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on IKEAFANS.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts. 

Some of our advertising partners use tracking cookies to serve the most relevant ads to you based on your browsing habits. You may opt out of these tracking cookies by visiting [this link](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to member needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes. 

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

### LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

Our site may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.   

### MONETIZING LINKS

Our site may contain links that have been monetized by placing affiliate code within links posted on the website. At times, links posted by members may be converted to affiliate links by software. IKEAFANS does not collect any personally identifiable information about what links are clicked on by members. Learn more about our [links monetized by VigLink.](http://www.viglink.com/policies/ftc?vgtag=badge)   

### CONTROLLING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will not sell, trade, give away, distribute, lease or share your personally identifiable information to or with third parties unless we have your express permission or are required to by law. We may use certain statistical data in order to provide you with pertinent information regarding IKEAFANS and/or offers, products, services or other information from IKEA. We may use your personal information to send you information about the site and its products and services which we think you may find interesting and if so, you will always have an option to opt-out. 

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please contact us. If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

If you have questions or concerns about this policy, please do not hesitate to contact us
